Register of the Lyn Nofziger Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ronald Reagan Related Materials, 1966-2004 (Box 10-11)
  - Speeches and writings, 1967-1994 (Folder 10)
    - About Reagan by others, 1968-1994 (Folder 10-11)
      - "The Reagan Administration and the Press: What's the problem?", 1984 March 1 (Folder 11: 1)
        From a session of the American Enterprise Institute. Panelists included Sam Donaldson, David Gergen, Jack Landau, Nofziger, Lou Cannon, and Victor Lasky
      - The Reason for Reagan, by M. Stanton Evans, 1968 March (Folder 11: 2)
      - Rollins, Ed campaign reflections, circa 1984 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Subject file, 1972-1982 (Folder 11)
    - Carter, Jimmy related documents, 1978 (Folder 11: 4)
    - Citizens for Reagan records, 1975 November (Folder 11: 5)
    - Citizens for the Republic clippings and memoranda, 1976-1977 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Franco, Lupe L. writings, 1972 (Folder 11: 7)
      Includes writings by Franco to Mexican American appointees in Reagan's gubernatorial administration
    - Office of Economic Opportunity (OEO) records, 1972 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act (TEFRA) public relations plan and correspondence, 1982 (Folder 11: 9)
  - Miscellany, letter to Kitty Kelley regarding her biography of Nancy Reagan, 1991 April 15 (Folder 11:11)
- Legal Proceedings and Related Documents, 1982-1991 (Box 11-16)
  Includes documents pertaining to various legal incidents in Nofziger's history. The bulk of the documentation regards United States vs. Nofziger, a violation of the Ethics in Government Act because of his lobbying for Wedtech Corporation. Materials arranged as follows: Clippings and press, Correspondence, Invoices and related correspondence, United States vs. Nofziger records, Nofziger's writings, Civil suits records and related materials, Wedtech Securities Litigation related civil suits, and Legal Defense Fund (LDF) records.
  - Clippings and press, 1986-1990 (Folder 11)
    - Nofziger and Bragg Communications new articles file, 1986-1957 (Folder 11: 12-15)
    - Nofziger and Bragg Communications news articles file, 1987-1989 (Folder 11: 16-19)
    - Trial related articles, 1986-1988 (Folder 12: 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1991 (Folder 12:3)
    Includes correspondence between Nofziger and his attorneys, correspondence from his attorneys to relevant parties, and related documents
  - Invoices and related correspondence, 1987-1990 (Folder 12:4)
    Includes invoices of legal fees with the firm Laxalt, Washington, Perito & Dubuc, correspondence with attorney Robert Plotkin, and other legal financial information
  - United States vs Nofziger records, 1987-1990 (Folder 12)
    - Indictment related legal documents, 1987-1988 (Folder 12: 5-6)
    - Arraignment document July 17, 1887, Motions Hearing & Status Call document, December 22, 1987 (Folder 12: 7)
    - "Confidential attorney work product: Wedtech Chronology,", 1987 June 15 (Folder 12: 8)
    - Press releases, 1987 July (Folder 12: 9)
    - United States vs. Nofziger records, 1987-1990 (Folder 12-14)
      - "Defendant Nofziger's Memorandum in Aid of Sentencing,", 1988 April 4 (Folder 12: 10-12)
        Includes memorandum and copies of related documents
      - "Defendant Nofziger's motion for Judgment of Acquittal, or in the Alternative, Motion for a New Trial,", 1988 February 22 (Folder 13: 1)
      - Interview of Nofziger by Independent Counsel James McKay, 1987 June-July (Folder 13: 2)
      - Jury information and instructions records, 1988 (Folder 13: 3)
      - Jury information, "Nofziger proposed Jury Instructions,", circa 1988 (Folder 13: 4)
      - Letter to Ronald Reagan, 1988 November 17 (Folder 13: 5)
        In letter Nofziger declined the option of a presidential pardon
      - "Memorandum" regarding Nofziger's motion for acquittal or a new trial, 1988 April 7 (Folder 13: 6)
      - McKay's closing arguments, 1988 February 9 (Folder 13: 7)
      - "Request for Enlargement of Time,", 1988 March 11 (Folder 13: 8)
        Consists of request from Nofziger's attorney from an extension of time between verdict and sentencing
      - "Transcript of Sentencing before the Honorable Thomas A. Flannery, United States District Judge,", 1988 April 8 (Folder 13: 9)
      - General trial related materials, 1982, 1988 (Folder 13: 10)
    - Appeals Court related records and documents, Appeal from the United States District Court for the District of Columbia (D.C. Crim. No. 87-309-01), Argued November 22, 1988 Decided June 27, 1989 (Folder 13: 11)
    - Appeals Court records, 1988 (Folder 13: 12)
    - Appeals Court records, 1988-1990 (Folder 14: 1-3)
    - Supreme Court records and documents, 1989 (Folder 14: 4)
    - "Legal Correspondence regarding Dismissal of Indictment,", 1990 (Folder 14: 5)
      Includes Congressional Research Service report "Legislative History and Purposes of Enactment of the Independent Counsel (Special Prosecutor) Provisions of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978"
    - "Order Dismissing Indictment,", 1990 January 10 (Folder 14: 6)
    - Petition for attorney fees legal records and related documentation, 1990-1991 (Folder 14: 7)
    - Related documents and Wedtech working papers, 1981-1983, 1985, 1987 (Folder 14: 8-10)
  - Nofziger's trial writings, circa 1988 (Folder 14-15)
    - Trial related diary, 1988 (Folder 14: 11-12)
      Details Nofziger's experiences in the days following the initial indictment
    - "A Trial Is Not a Tribulation," a collection of verse regarding each day of the trial, circa 1988 (Folder 15: 1)
    - Trial reflections and legally required writings, circa 1988 (Folder 15: 2)
  - Civil suits records and related materials, 1984, 1990, 1992, 1995 (Folder 15:3)
    Includes records and documentation regarding other legal actions involving Nofziger not directly related to the litigation regarding his alleged violation of the Ethics in Government Act
  - Wedtech Securities Litigation related civil suits, 1987-1990 (Folder 15:4-6)
  - Legal Defense Fund (LDF) records, circa 1987-1988 (Folder 15-16)
    - Accounting and financial records, 1987-1988 (Folder 15: 7)
    - Contributors information and records, circa 1987-1988 (Folder 15: 8-9)
    - Contributor letters, A-H, circa 1987-1988 (Folder 15: 10)
      Some letters sent in Nofziger's name, some sent to individuals in charge of the LDF. If letter is not to Nofziger, arrangement is according to the name of the individual sending the letter
    - Contributor letters, H-M, circa 1987-1988 (Folder 16: 1)
    - Contributor letters, small-size letters, postcards, and greeting cards, circa 1987-1988 (Folder 16: 2)
- Political Consulting records, 1969-1999 (Box 16)
  Includes documents pertaining to various political campaigns in which Nofziger played a role, as well as Nofziger's notes regarding Republican party use of propaganda. Arranged alphabetically by candidate
  - Beall, J. Glenn, circa 1970-1971 (Folder 16: 3)
    Includes statements made by or about J. Glenn Beall while running for Senator from Maryland
  - Buchanan, Pat, 1999 (Folder 16: 4)
    Participated in fund raising via Citizens for the Republic for Buchanan's 2000 presidential primary campaign
  - Bush, Prescott, 1982, 1992 (Folder 16: 5)
    Includes correspondence between Nofziger and Prescott Bush and George H.W. Bush as well as articles regarding Nofziger's assistance to George H.W. Bush in the 1992 presidential campaign
  - Dole, Bob, correspondence, 1996 (Folder 16: 6)
  - Rafferty, Max, 1968, undated (Folder 16: 7)
    Includes speeches by Rafferty and Nofziger's thoughts regarding Rafferty
  - Reinecke, Ed, circa 1970s, 1971-1974 (Folder 16)
    - Reinecke Advisory Council records, circa 1970s, 1973-1974 (Folder 16: 8-10)
    - Reinecke Campaign Documents, 1972-1973 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Thorness, Leo, 1974 (Folder 16: 12)
    Includes Nofziger's letter of resignation and subsequent press release in light of Nofziger's involvement in the 1972 Nixon campaign and related press clippings
  - Nofziger's notes regarding propaganda, 1969-1970 (Folder 16: 13-14)
  - Miscellany, 1971-1972 (Folder 16: 15)
- Collected documents and clippings, 1958-1986, circa 1950s-2000s, undated (Box 17-19)
  Includes materials collected by Nofziger on certain topics of interest. Arranged in two groups: Documents and Clippings.
  - Documents, 1958-1999 (Folder 17)
    - An American Life by Jeb Magruder, circa 1974 (Folder 17: 1)
    - Institute for Contemporary Studies documents and notes, 1975 (Folder 17: 2)
      Consists of criticism of the Ford Foundation Energy Policy Project
    - Korean rice issues documents, 1982-1984 (Folder 17: 3-5)
    - Latin American Management Association(LAMA) Issues Conference Announcement, 1986 (Folder 17: 6)
      Includes information regarding Nofziger's appearance at LAMA's earlier conference
    - "Memorandum Regarding PM Suzuki, Foreign Minister_____, Finance Minister Watanabe, Energy Minister Hokahara,", undated (Folder 17: 7)
    - Natts key member list, 1985 February (Folder 17: 8)
    - "Proposed research to reduce racial aspects of the environment-heredity uncertainty,", 1958 (Folder 17: 9)
    - Miscellany, "Materials for notebooks on Lyn,", circa 1973-1990 (Folder 17: 10)
      Consists of a clippings, correspondence, writings by Nofziger and broadcasts
  - Clippings, circa 1950s-2000s (Box 17-19)
    Includes newspaper and other press clippings directly or indirectly referring to Nofziger. Arranged chronologically
    - 1960s-1980s (Folder 17: 11)
      bound together
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 17: 12)
    - 1960s (Folder 17: 13-15)
    - 1970s (Folder 17: 16)
    - 1970s (Folder 18: 1-2)
    - 1980-1983 (Folder 18: 3)
    - 1982 (Folder 18: 4)
    - 1980-1985 (Folder 18: 5-6)
    - 1986-1987 (Folder 19: 1)
    - 1987-1988 (Folder 19: 2)
    - 1988-1989 (Folder 19: 3)
    - 1980s, undated (Folder 19: 4)
    - 1992-1993 (Folder 19: 5)
    - 1990s (Folder 19: 6)
    - 2000s (Folder 19: 7)
    - undated (Folder 19: 8)
- Photographs, circa 1960s-1990s, undated (Box 19-20)
  Includes autographed photographs from various high ranking officials in the first Reagan presidential administration and images from Nofziger's time with the Nixon Administration as well as additional images featuring Nofziger at both public and private events.
  - Autographed photographs, circa 1981-1982 (Folder 19: 9)
    Includes images of Everett Alvarez, Martin Anderson, James Baker, Malcolm Balridge, Terrel Bell, William Bennett, William E. Brock III, Bill Casey, Elizabeth Dole, Jim Edwards, Alexander Haig, John Stewart Herrington
  - Autographed photographs, circa 1981-1982 (Folder 20: 1)
    Includes images of Donald Hodel, Jeane Kirkpatrick, Drew Lewis, Edwin Meese, Sam Pierce, Donald Regan, Richard Schweiker, George Shultz, William Frank Smith, James G. Watt, Caspar Weinberger
  - Autographed photographs, undated (Folder 20: 2)
  - Nixon's White House administration portraits, circa 1968-1974 (Folder 20: 3)
  - Nixon administration portrait, circa 1973 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Nofziger at various speaking events and gatherings, circa 1970s-1980s (Folder 20: 5)
  - Miscellaneous prints, circa 1970s-1990s (Folder 20: 6)
  - Reagan and Dwight Eisenhower images, circa 1960s (Folder 20: 7)
  - Slides, 1984 May (Folder 20: 8)
- Memorabilia, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 21, 23)
  Includes pins, ribbons, press passes, other cards, sketches, buttons from various political campaigns, calendars containing Nofziger's personal schedules, posters and programs featuring him prominently.
  - Cartoon featuring Nofziger and Ronald Reagan regarding TEFRA, circa 1982 (Folder 20: 9)
  - "Inauguration Souvenir. Pictoral History. Candidates, Cabinet Officers, Ladies of the White House, and Principal Events, 1864-1983,", 1893 March 4 (Folder 20: 10)
  - Posters and programs featuring Nofziger, 1981, 1983, 1986, undated (Folder 20: 11)
  - Press passes, convention passes and related materials, circa 1950s-1960s (Folder 20: 12)
  - Ronald Reagan's badge from the National Conference of State Legislative Leaders 1967 Convention (Folder 20: 13)
  - Ronald Reagan bumper sticker, circa 1980s (Folder 20: 14)
  - Republican party pins and pendants, undated (Folder 21: 1)
  - Ribbons and press passes, 1967, undated (Folder 21: 2)
  - Stickers from the Committee for the Re-election of the President, circa 1972 and stamp featuring Richard Nixon and Spiro Agnew, 1973 January 20, circa 1972, 1973 January 20 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Buttons, circa 1960s-1980s (Folder 21: 4)
    Includes buttons from various campaigns and general Republican support
  - Calendars, 1971-1972 (Folder 23)
    Includes handwritten notations regarding his appointments and travelling schedules
- Audiovisual File, 1976, 1980, undated (Box 22)
  Includes 9 phonotape reels, 1 one inch open reel videotape, and 1 motion picture reel. The bulk of the materials relate to Reagan's 1976 Republican presidential primary campaign.
  - Citizens for Reagan, Eight Radio Spots, circa 1976 (Folder 22: 1)
  - Citizens for Reagan, Unusual Request, 1976 June 6 (Folder 22: 2-4)
    A 60 second spot in response to radio spots by Gerald Ford. Includes a letter from Citizens for Reagan and a transcript of the spot itself. 3 copies.
  - Gerald Ford, State of the Union speech, 1976 January 19 (Folder 22: 5)
  - Helms for Reagan, undated (Folder 22: 6)
  - Reel 2 - P.M. session, undated (Folder 22: 7)
  - Dennis Rafferty, undated (Folder 22: 8)
  - Untitled, undated (Folder 22: 9)
  - "Pat: A Tribute to the First Lady,", undated; 16mm print, color, sound, 400ft. (Film shelf Film shelf)
    Access
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 2010c32_f_0011013.
    A documentary short narrated by James Stewart and focusing on Pat Nixon's contributions as First Lady of the United States. Label reads: "White House copy."
  - "Election Eve" series, "Disclaimer and Closing Montage,", 1980 October 30 (Videotape Videotape Shelf)
    1 inch open-reel videotape, Master copy, client: Fiorenterio, ident: Reagan/Dallas SMU, dub